http://www.alco-valves.com/privacy-policy/

Brochure Downloads
We use cookies to give you the best online experience. By using this website you agree with our cookie policy
1. Introduction
1.1 We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors, service users and vendors.
1.2 This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to the personal data of our website visitors, service users and vendors; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data.
1.3 Our website incorporates privacy controls which affect how we will process your personal data. By using the privacy controls, you can specify whether you would like to receive direct marketing communications. You can access the privacy controls via or Unsubscribe links at the bottom of marketing emails. You can also contact us at any time to request removal.
1.4 In this policy, “we”, “us” and “our” refer to Alco Valves Group as the data controller. For more information about us, see Section 12.
2. How we use your personal data
2.1 In this section we have set out:
(a) the general categories of personal data that we may process;
(b) in the case of personal data that we did not obtain directly from you, the source and specific categories of that data;
(c) the purposes for which we may process personal data; and
(d) the legal bases of the processing.
2.2 We may process data about your use of our website and services. The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. The source of the usage data is our analytics tracking system (see Google Analytics Privacy Policy: https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en) and online live chat facility (see Zendesk Privacy Policy: www.zendesk.co.uk/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy). This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analysing the use of the website and services. The legal basis for this processing is for our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services. Where we collect data via our live chat website facility, the basis for this processing is for contact means only, where we are able to establish communication for prolonged queries or better deal with other queries in the future (recurring visits).
2.3 We may process account / profile data. If you are a customer or vendor purchasing our products or service(s) or supplying a service to us. We may process your information, which may include your name, email address, telephone number(s) and location address(es). The source of the account data is you or your employer. The account data may be processed for the purposes of providing our services to you, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the administration and operation of our website and business.
2.4 We may process information contained in any enquiry you submit to us regarding goods and/or services. The enquiry data may be processed for the purposes of offering, marketing and selling relevant goods and/or services to you. The legal basis for this processing is legitimate business purposes.
2.5 We may process information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services, that you enter into with us. This may include your contact details, banking / payment details and details of any relevant transactions. The transaction data may be processed for the purpose of supplying goods and services. The legal basis for this processing and keeping records of transactions is for the administration of our business, as well as the contract between you and us / taking steps to enter into such a contract and our legitimate interests.
2.6 We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters. The notification data may be processed for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters. The source of this usage data is Mailchimp (see Mailchimp Privacy Policy: https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy). The legal basis for this processing is consent.
2.7 We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of other parties.
2.8 Please do not supply any other person’s personal data to us, unless we prompt you to do so.
3. Providing your personal data to others
3.1 We may disclose your personal data to our parent company as reasonably necessary for the purposes, and on the legal bases, set out in this policy.
3.2 We may disclose your personal data to our insurers and/or professional advisers as reasonably necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, credit checks, watch lists, security, managing risks, obtaining professional advice, or the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.
3.3 Financial transactions relating to our products and services may be handled by our payment services providers (Lloyds Banking Group). We will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing payments, refunding payments and / or dealing with queries relating to such payments and refunds. You can find information about the payment services providers’ privacy policies and practices at www.lloydsbank.com/business/privacy.
3.4 In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this section, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another party. We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.
4. International transfers of your personal data
4.1 In this section, we provide information about the circumstances in which your personal data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA).
4.2 Alco Valves Group has offices and facilities in various countries worldwide including the United States, Singapore, Malaysia, Australia and the United Arab Emirates. Each of these locations abides by the data protection laws outlined within this policy.
5. Retaining and deleting personal data
5.1 This section sets out our data retention policies and procedures, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data.
5.2 Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary.
5.3 We will retain your personal data as follows:
(a) Customer personal data will be retained for a maximum period of 10 years. This is due to requirements for the Pressure Equipment Directives (PED). Further information can be made readily available.
(b) Vendor personal data will be retained for a maximum period of 10 years.
(c) Alco Valves Group staff / personnel personal data will be retained for a minimum period of 2 years and for a maximum period of 6 years following termination date.
5.4 Notwithstanding the other provisions of this section, we may retain personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or to protect vital interests or the vital interests of another party.
6. Amendments
6.1 We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website.
6.2 We encourage checking this page every 6 months to ensure that you are satisfied with any changes to this policy.
6.3 We will notify you of significant changes to this policy by email / newsletter or through the news section on our website or if required, our social media platforms.
7. Your rights
7.1 In this section, we have summarised the rights that you have under data protection law. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights. A general outline can be found at the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) at www.ico.org.uk
7.2 Your principal rights under data protection law are:
(a) the right to access;
(b) the right to rectification;
(c) the right to erasure;
(d) the right to restrict processing;
(e) the right to object to processing;
(f) the right to data portability;
(g) the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and
(h) the right to withdraw consent.
7.3 You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. You may request copies of data in writing or verbally. For efficiency purposes we may ask you to complete a Subject Access Request Form. Copies of data may be subject to a reasonable fee.
7.4 You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.
7.5 In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances may include: the data is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which it was initially collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.
7.6 In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful, but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or for the protection of the rights of another party.
7.7 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.
7.8 You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose. You can also manage and unsubscribe from our mailing lists by following the Manage and Unsubscribe links at the bottom of our marketing emails or contacting us directly (see contact details in Section 13).
7.9 To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is:
(a) consent; or
(b) that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract,
and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.
7.10 If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. In the United Kingdom this is the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) www.ico.org.uk. You may also check with the relevant authority in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.
7.11 To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.
7.12 You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by submitting written notice to us, in addition to the other methods specified in this section.
8. About cookies
8.1 A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.
8.2 Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.
8.3 Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.
9. Cookies that we use
9.1 We use cookies for the following purposes:
(a) authentication – we use persistent cookies to identify you when you visit our website and download brochures. Simply, the website ‘remembers’ your email address so you do not have to repeatedly enter it to enable downloads.
(b) personalisation – we use cookies to store information about your preferences and to personalise the website for you.
(c) analysis – we use cookies to help us to analyse the use and performance of our website and services.
(d) cookie consent – we use cookies to store your preferences in relation to the use of cookies more generally.
10. Cookies used by our service providers
10.1 Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website.
10.2 We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: www.google.com/policies/privacy/.
11. Managing cookies
11.1 Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser and from version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:
(a) www.support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en (Chrome);
(b) www.support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences (Firefox);
(c) www.support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies (Internet Explorer);
(d) www.support.apple.com/kb/PH21411 (Safari); and
(e) www.privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy (Edge).
Please note: the above list is not exhaustive.
11.2 Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.
11.3 If you block cookies, you may not be able to use all the features on our website.
11.4
If you would like further information on cookies, you can visit www.aboutcookies.org
12. Our details
12.1 The Alco website is owned and operated by Alco Valves Group.
12.2 We are registered in England and Wales under registration number 03664462, and our registered office is at Gooder Lane, Brighouse, West Yorkshire, HD6 1HB, United Kingdom, which is also our principal place of business.
12.3 You can contact us:
(a) by post, to the postal address given above;
(b) using our website contact form(s) at www.alco-valves.com;
(c) by telephone, on +44 (0)1484 710511;
(d) by email, using privacy@alco-valves.com.
13. Data Controller
13.1 Alco Valves Group Data Controller – Damien Archer (damien.archer@alco-valves.com)
IT Department
Email Communication Disclaimer
Opinions expressed or statements made in any Alco Valves Group communication are those of the individual and not necessarily those of the Company.
Email communications and any files transmitted with them are confidential and solely for the use of the named or intended recipient(s). If you should find that an email is sent to you via Alco Valves Group and you are not the named or intended recipient, or the person responsible for delivering to such a person, you are requested to notify us via return email and destroy the original message and any copies along with any attached files from your computer system. Any dissemination, distribution or copying of this communication or its attachments by you is strictly prohibited and may be illegal.
If you wish to forward a message or attached files to any non-UK entity, you must ensure that you have all necessary trade and/or export control provisions or licences in place beforehand and likewise for any business that may be conducted as a result of the forwarded message.
Email communication are not intended to create or amend any binding contract between us (including offering any warranties, guarantees or indemnities), except when it is supported by written confirmation on paper bearing the Company’s logo and signed by a duly authorised representative of the Company. All transactions with us are subject to our standard terms and conditions which are available upon request or here:
[view our conditions of sale and purchase]
Please note that a quotation from us does not constitute an offer to contract with us but invites the recipient to submit an offer to purchase goods from us. Contracts of sale with us are formed only when an acknowledgement is made in writing by us. It should be noted that any communication with us or emails you send to the Company may be monitored by systems or persons other than the communicant, for the purposes of ascertaining whether the communication complies with the law and with the Company’s policies. Those communicating with us by electronic means will be deemed to have accepted the risks associated with such method, being interception, unauthorised amendment, late or incomplete delivery.
Whilst we check email communications for viruses, we do not accept responsibility or liability for any loss or damage caused by this communication and/or attached files containing viruses. It is recommended that you check the content and attachments of this/all messages from us using an appropriate anti-virus program/protection. If you have any questions or require further information regarding this subject matter, please contact itsupport@alco-valves.com.
This Company is a limited liability company. All commercial activities and trading is subject to the law prevailing in the country of the Alco Group Company’s registration.
Please note we do not wish to receive unsolicited communications of any kind and, unless otherwise requested, we do not wish to be part of any mailing list. Alco Valves Group abides GDPR legislation. Read our Privacy Statement for more information.
Disclaimer Copyright © 2020.
Sign up for updates on Alco Valves latest news, products and company developments.
Submit
Founded in 1977 Alco Valves Ltd was incorporated with the express purpose of manufacturing a comprehensive range of technically advanced, precision made, high integrity valve products and accessories.
Terms and conditions / Privacy policy
Terms and conditions / Privacy policy
PRODUCTS
INSTRUMENTATION
DBB VALVES
XC DBB VALVES
SUBSEA
COMPANY
Alco Valves Group, Gooder Lane, Brighouse, HD6 1HB, United Kingdom
+44 (0) 1484 710511 info@alco-valves.com
© 2020 Alco Valves Group
